Ahimsha Satya Graha

Semarang City, Central Java

ahimshasatyag@gmail.com | +6281226641337 | www.linkedin.com/in/ahimshasatyag

SUMMARY

I am very goal-oriented and passionate about working with people to achieve their goals while fulfilling their potential. Reliable, agile in a fast-paced environment, proactive, strong work ethic, and rapidly learning new tasks. Competent at work, tech-savvy, and experienced in creating websites and analyze data.

KEY SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

Skillset: Analytical, Critical Thinking, Networking, Problem Solving,

Videography, Photography

Toolset: Looker Studio, Power BI, Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Power Point)

Figma, Canva, Adobe (Photoshop, After Effect, Premiere Pro)

Progamming: Javascript, Bootstrap, PHP, Python, SQL

Platforms: Jupyter Notebook, Visual Studio Code, Google Colab

LANGUAGES

Indonesian (native), English (Intermediate)

EXPERIENCE

Digital Marketing Internship

November 2023 – January 2024

- This design is the result of determined marketing with various themes involving an iterative process where ideas are developed, evaluated, and modified to achieve a satisfactory final result.
- Prepare interesting social media content that increases Instagram engagement by up to 10% within 3 months.
- Constantly update with social media trends and create trend-relavant content.

MSIB at PT Revolusi Cita Edukasi

August – Desember 2023

Data and Software Engineering

- Learn the basics of python, javascript, PHP programming and learn google tools like Sheets, Data Studio, BigQuery, etc.
- Practice the concept of understanding learning in this field in the industrial world
- Developed website delivery of goods with javascript programming and create dashboard reports to analyze problems shopping cart

MSIB at PT Presentologics

August – December 2022

Front-End Web and React.Js

- Learn basics of javascript progamming and library React.js
- Learning and training to create a website with completed tasks.
- Developing a simple website with a psychology theme using the React.js library

ORGANIZER EXPERIENCES

Badan Eksekutif Mahasiswa Keluarga Mahasiswa Universitas Dian Nuswantoro Wakil Menteri Sosial Masyarakat August 2022 – July 2023

- Accommodates community service activities both in social and disaster issues such as bakti social, berbagi makanan, etc.
- Establish relationships and coordinate with various related parties such as other campus BEM departments.
- Assist the head of the ministry in planning, organizing and implementing

ministry programs.

Wakil Direktorat Jenderal Komunikasi dan Informasi

October 2021 - July 2022

- Assisting the chairman and conveying to members in carrying out work programs related to Komunikasi dan Informasi.
- Create information such as social media creating Instagram feeds, documenting activities, and making designs.

Dian Nuswatoro Computer Club

Staff Division Multimedia ·

June 2021 - June 2022

- Providing information services to the public.
- Capturing or taking pictures of an activity to be documented.
- Designing social media feeds.

Sineas Muda Semarang

Kameramen ·

September 2021 - Now

- Operate the camera during shooting, both for video recording and live broadcast.
- Adjust camera settings and shooting techniques according to changing situations in the field.
- Review and evaluate recordings to ensure quality and suitability to production needs.

EDUCATION

Dian Nuswantoro University

Semarang City, Central Java

Bachelor of Computer Science – GPA 3,44

July 2020 – April 2024

PROJECTS

Data Analysis

Shopping Cart - Link

- Analyze how to increase sales to 10%-20% despite peak or off-peak season from month to month within a year.
- The dataset that focusing on is ranging from January 2021 October 2021.
- This dataset will visualize the results that have been analyzed in Looker Studio.

Front End Web

Delivery of Goods - Link

- Create logo designs and responsive website layout sketches.
- Using HTML and CSS layout programming languages responsive website.
- Create goods delivery features such as lacak pemesanan, estimasi biaya, cek outlet.

Data Scientist Machine Learning

Speech-Based Emotion Classification using a Support Vector Machine Algorithm-Link

- Determine the classification performance of the Support Vector Machine algorithm in emotion classification.
- The sound emotions that will be classified include angry, sad, happy, neutral, and surprise.
- Research using several features to determine the best performance.

Digital Marketing

Level Up by Amoeba (Telkomsel) - Link

- Create captions and monthly content plans that will be posted.
- Create edit designs for Instagram feeds and stories.
- Document and create short videos of event activities.

LICENSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

Level Up by Amoeba

Telkomsel · Digital Marketing
Assessed and certified by Telkomsel

Amazon Web Service

Cloud Foundation
Assessed and certified by Amazon Web Service Academy

Magang dan Studi Independen Bersertifikat Batch 5

RevoU · Data and Software Engineering
Assessed and certified by PT Revolusi Cita Edukasi

Magang dan Studi Independen Bersertifikat Batch 3

Dicoding · Front End Web and React Assessed and certified by PT Presentologics

Digital Talent Scholarship

Junior Web Developer Assessed and certified by Kementerian Komunikasi dan Informatika